Guide to the Recordsings of Sunrise Semester Programs RG.7.3.1.1
New York University Archives
- "Discipline in the Classroom: Social and Emotional Problems" with Professor Dr. Lawrence Balter, September 21, 1977 - January 6, 1978
  - Episode #46, "Semester Wrap-Up", December 19, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0300)
    Guest lecturer: Dean Daniel Griffiths; Air date: January 6, 1978
  - Cue sheets, 1977-1978 (Box Shared University Archives 156, Folder 9, 10)
- "Man's Place in Nature" with Professor Dr. John Buettner-Janusch, September, 1977
  - Video recording, September 20, 1977; cuid18699 (Box 60, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0400)
  - Video recording, September 20, 1977; cuid18700 (Box 61, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0479)
  - Cue sheets, 1977 (Box Shared University Archives 156, Folder 11)
- "Media Ecology" with Marshall McLuhan, October, 1977; cuid18790
  - "Laws of Media" Discussion with Fairleigh Dickinson, Part 1, cuid18793
    McLuhan leads a discussion at a lecture hall at the School of Dentistry. The discussion on technology explores environmental effects of technology, intellectual decline from over stimulation, and McLuhan's "Laws of Media." The video ends abruptly.
    - Original video recording, cuid18794 (Box 7, Half inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0389)
    - Access DVD (Box 14, Dvd 1:22)
  - "Laws of Media" Discussion with Fairleigh Dickinson, Part 2, cuid18791
    The majority of the discussion is based on McLuhan's four "Laws of Media" which are Enhance, Reverse, Retrieve, and Obsolescence. He also discusses the study of technology, American advertising, and the effects of politicians becoming known by the general public. The video ends with questions from the audience.
    - Original video recording, cuid18792 (Box 7, Half inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0392)
    - Access DVD (Box 14, Dvd 1:21)
- "Physics and Society" with Professor Dr. Benjamin Bederson, April, 1978
  - Episode #43, April 18, 1978; cuid18702 (Box 45, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0444)
  - Episode #45, April 18, 1978; cuid18703 (Box 46, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0399)
- "Teaching Critical Reading and Thinking to Children and Adolescents" with Professor Dr. Bernice Cullian, April, 1978
  - Episode #41, April 20, 1978; cuid18705 (Box 48, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0524)
  - Episode #45, April 19, 1978; cuid18704 (Box 47, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0465)
- "Paradox US", May, 1978
  - Episode #7, May 7, 1978; cuid18706 (Box 22, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0405)
  - Episode #46, May 23, 1978; cuid18709 (Box 25, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0482)
- "Future", May, 1978
  - Episode #27, May 22, 1978; cuid18708 (Box 24, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0475)
  - Episode #28, undated (Box 23, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0551)
- "C Eliminator" -- Episode #3, June 21, 1978; cuid18707 (Box 49, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0469)
- "The English Language Arts: Creative Teaching of Speaking, Listening, and Writing to Children and Adolescents" with Professor Charles Reasoner, September, 1978
  - Episode #10, September 25, 1978; cuid18710 (Box 50, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0483)
  - Episode #12, September 25. 1978; cuid18711 (Box 51, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0480)
- "The American Character" with Professor Dr. Herbert London -- Episode #28, September 26, 1978; cuid18712 (Box 52, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0404)
- "Content Area Teaching: Reading Problems and Strategies" with Professor Dr. M. Trika Smith-Burke, January - February, 1979
  - Episode #16, January 22, 1979 (Box 313, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0429)
  - Episode #23, February 21, 1979; cuid18713 (Box 288, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0525)
- "R" -- Episode #26, March 19, 1979 (Box 295, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0453)
- "Suburbia", March - April, 1979
  - "5-118 A", March 8, 1979; cuid18714 (Box 265, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0454)
  - "105-5", April 5, 1979; cuid18715 (Box 269, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0397)
- "Drama in Education" with Professor Robert Landy, August - October, 1979
  - "D" Episode #312, August 9, 1979 (Box 361, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0513)
  - "M" Episode #15, October 4, 1979 (Box 344, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0526)
  - "M" Episode #25, October 15, 1979; cuid18716 (Box 297, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0398)
  - "M" Episode #17, October 17, 1979 (Box 56, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0173)
  - Access DVD, undated (Box 15, Dvd AV3481)
- "Learning to Write / Writing to Learn" with Professor Dr. John Mayher, January 16 - May 9, 1980
  - Episode #1, January 9, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0240)
    Air dates: January 28-29, 1980
  - Episode #2, "Writing: Who Is It For? What Is Its Purpose?", January 9, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0241)
    Includes voiceovers by Nancy Mayher and Gordon Pradl; Air dates: January 30-31, 1980
  - Episode #3, "Categorizing Types of Writing by Purpose, Function, and Audience", January 9, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0242)
    Guest lecturer: Gordon M. Pradl; Air dates: February 1-2, 1980
  - Episode #4, "What Is Really Happening In Writing In Schools?", January 23, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0233)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Stephen Koziol; Air dates: February 4-5, 1980
  - Episode #5, "Writing: The Teacher's Role", January 16, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0234)
    Guest lecturers: Dale Boyd, Cynthia Onore, Karen Shawn, Bucky Nichau; Air dates: February 6-7, 1980
  - Episode #6, "How We Learn Through Writing", January 16, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0235)
    Guest lecturer: Prof. Gordon Pradl (V.O.); Air dates: February 8-9, 1980
  - Episode #7, "Journals: Initial Examples of Writer-Based Prose", January 16, 1980
    Guest lecturer: Fred Grossberg; Label also reads: "Molly's story"; Air date: February 10, 1980
    - Audio recording (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0236)
    - Video recording, cuid18717 (Box 44, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0474)
  - Episode #8, "Journals: Appropriate Teacher Response Strategies", January 23, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0237)
    Label also reads "Lisa Ann's story"; Air dates: February 13-14, 1980
  - Episode #9, "Journals: Revision Towards Reder-Based Prose", January 23, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0238)
    Air dates: February 15-16, 1980
  - Episode #10, "Language Development: Emerging Grammars of Proficiencies", January 30, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0239)
    Guest lecturer: Rita S. Brause; Air dates: February 18-19, 1980
  - Episode #11, "The Importance of Narrative in Developing Linguistic Abilities", January 30, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0226)
    Guest lecturer: Gordon Pradl; Air dates: February 20-21, 1980
  - Episode #12, "Oral and Written Stories: The Initial Language of Self", January 30, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0227)
    Guest lecturers: Gordon M. Pradl, Dr. John Rouse; Air dates: February 22-23, 1980
  - Episode #13, "Characteristics of Beginning Writers in the Elementary and Junior High School", February 4, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0228)
    Guest lecturer: Lucy McCormick Calkins; Air dates: February 25-26, 1980
  - Episode #14, "Characteristics of Mature Writers", February 4, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0229)
    Guest lecturer: Lee Odell; Air dates: February 27-28, 1980
  - Episode #15, "Characteristics of Basic Writers", February 4, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0230)
    Guest lecturer: Sondra Perl; Air dates: February 29 - March 1, 1980
  - Episode #16, "Language As A System: Many Grammars", February 6, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0231)
    Air dates: March 3-4, 1980
  - Episode #17, "Role of Grammar in the Teaching of Writing", February 6, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0232)
    Guest lecturer: Karen Greenberg; Air dates: March 6-8, 1980
  - Episode #18, "Editing: Enriching the Syntactic Complexity of a Text; Sentence Combining", February 6, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0220)
    March 7-8, 1980
  - Episode #19, "The Nature of Languages and Dialects", February 13, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0222)
    Air dates: March 10-11, 1980
  - Episode #20, "The Effect of Dialect Interference in Writing", February 13, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0221)
    Guest lecturer: Barbara Q. Gray; Air dates: March 12-13, 1980
  - Episode #21, "Reading and Writing / Reading and Spelling", February 13, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0223)
    Air dates: March 14-15, 1980
  - Episode #22, "Talking and Writing", February 20, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0224)
    Guest lecturers: Dale Boyd and students; Air dates: March 17-18, 1980
  - Episode #23, "Drama, Writing and Talking", February 20, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0225)
    Label also reads: "Grossterz's inserts"; Air dates: March 19-20, 1980
  - Episode #24 -- Empty Case, February 20, 1980 (Box 2)
    Air dates: March 21-22, 1980
  - Episode #25, February 26, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0213)
    Air dates: March 24-25, 1980
  - Episode #26, "Generating Assignments: The Student's Role", undated
    Guest lecturers: Harold H. Vine, Jr., Prof. Martha J. Bell
    - Audio recording (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0214)
    - Video recording (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0178)
  - Episode #27, March 5, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0215)
    Air dates: March 26-27, 1980
  - Episode #28, "Getting Started in the Composing Process: From Writer-Based to Reader-Based Prose", February 26, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0216)
    Guest lecturer: Linda Flower; Air dates: March 31 - April 1, 1980
  - Episode #29, "How to Intervene in the Composing Process", February 26, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0217)
    Air dates: April 2-3, 1980
  - Episode #30, "How Teacher Feedback Can Help and Hurt", March 5, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0218)
    Guest lecturer: Gordon Pradl; Air dates: April 4-5, 1980
  - Episode #31, "Collaboration and Writing Groups", March 14, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0219)
    Guest lecturers: Dale Boyd and students; Air dates: April 7-8, 1980
  - Episode #32, "The Role of Audience in Shaping", March 14, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0206)
    Air dates: April 9-10, 1980
  - Episode #33, "Creating Real Audiences for Writing", March 10, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0207)
    Air dates: April 11-12, 1980
  - Episode #34, "The Revising and Editing Process", March 19, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0208)
    Guest lecturers: Maria Zini, Faye Peitzman; Air dates: April 14-15, 1980
  - Episode #35, "Using Groups to Revise and Edit", March 19, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0209)
    Guest lecturer: Mary K. Healy; Air dates: April 16-17, 1980
  - Episode #36, "Helping the Basic Writer", April 9, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0210)
    Guest lecturer: Sondra Perl; Air dates: April 18-19, 1980
  - Episode #37, "Composing as a Recursive Process", April 9, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0211)
    Guest lecturers: Janet Emig, Diane Hilsen, Carmen Collins, Norman Elmore, Anthony Scannella; Air dates: April 21-22, 1980
  - Episode #38, "Shaping at the Point of Utterance: Integrating the Writing Process within the Writing Product", March 12, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0212)
    Guest lecturers: James Britton, Gordon Pradl; Air dates: April 23-24, 1980
  - Episode #39, "Writing Assignments Across the Curriculum", April 16, 1980
    Guest lecturer: Robert Parker, Jr.; Air dates: April 25-26, 1980
    - Audio recording (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0203)
    - Video recording (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0191)
  - Episode #40, "The Place of Writing in the School Environment", March 12, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0201)
    Guest lecturer: James Britton; Air dates: April 28-29, 1980
  - Episode #41, "Learning and Writing in Science and Math", March 19, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0202)
    Guest lecturer: Mary K. Healy; Air dates: April 30 and May 1, 1980.
  - Episode #42, "Learning and Writing in the Arts", April 9, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0204)
    Guest lecturer: Philip Lopate; Air dates: May 2-3, 1980
  - Episode #43, "Assessing Writing Growth: Process and Product", March 12, 1980 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0205)
    Guest lecturer: James Britton; Air dates: May 5-6, 1980
  - Episode #44, "Assessing Writing Growth: Process and Product" and "#44 Collaborative Strategies for Judging Student Writing" (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0243)
    Guest lecturers: Paul B. Johnson, Cy Knohlanch; Air dates: May 7-8, 1980
  - Episode #45, "Concluding Perspectives", April 16, 1980
    Guest lecturers: Ramsey Lester Mayher, Gordon M. Pradl; Air dates: May 9-10, 1980
    - Audio recording (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0244)
    - Video recording (Box 10, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0198)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #2, Episode #3 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0180)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #4, Episode #5 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0181)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #4, Episode #5 (Box 7, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0200)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #6, Episode #7 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0182)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #8, Episode #9 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0183)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #10, Episode #11 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0184)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #12, Episode #13 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0185)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #14, Episode #15 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0188)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #16, Episode #17 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0187)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #18, Episode #19 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0186)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #20, Episode #21 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0177)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #22, Episode #23 (Box 8, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0179)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #28, Episode #29 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0197)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #30, Episode #31 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0196)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #32, Episode #33 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0195)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #34, Episode #35 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0194)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #36, Episode #37 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0193)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #38, Episode #39 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0192)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #41, Episode #42 (Box 9, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0190)
  - Video Compilation -- Episode #43, Episode #44 (Box 10, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0189)
  - Inserts, January 24, 1980
    - Audio recording -- First tape (Inserts #1-3), January 24, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0246)
    - Audio recording -- Second tape (Insert #4), January 24, 1980 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0245)
    - Video recording, undated (Box 10, U-matic 7.3.1.1.0199)
- "Fourteen Hundred Years of Islam" with Professor Peter Chelkowski, February, 1980 - March, 1982
  - Episode #19, February 5, 1980; cuid18718 (Box 304, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0467)
  - Episode #33, March 18, 1982; cuid18725 (Box 302, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0508)
- "World U", May, 1980
  - Episode #7, May 14 1980; cuid18719 (Box 40, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0510)
  - Episode #12, May 21, 1980 (Box 264, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0172)
- "Italian SJ", May - June, 1981
  - Episode #3, May 26, 1981 (Box 21, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0486)
  - Episode #10, June 1, 1981 (Box 17, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0547)
- "Industrial B", May - June, 1981
  - Episode #2, May 5, 1981 (Box 266, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0553)
  - Episode #9, June 2, 1981 (Box 332, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0548)
- "The Legacy of Israel" with Dr. Baruch A. Levine, September, 1980 - December, 1982
  - Episode #3, September 15, 1980 (Box 55, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0174)
  - Episode #38, December 1, 1982 (Box 20, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0175)
- "The City in American Literature" with Professor Dr. James Tuttleton, September - October, 1980
  - Episode #1, September 16, 1980; cuid18720 (Box 299, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0473)
  - Episode #16, October 14, 1980; cuid18721 (Box 303, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0433)
- "Women and Men in a Changing Society" with Dr. Marilyn Young and Dr. Ellen Ross, January - March, 1981
  - Episode #1, January 6, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0004)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    This reel was isolated for visible mold in 2022.
    Air dates: January 26-27, 1981
  - Episode #2, January 6, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0011)
    Air dates: January 28-29, 1981
  - Episode #4, January 13, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0012)
    Guest lecturer: Josah B. Pomoroy [label somewhat illegible]; Air dates: February 2-3, 1981
  - Episode #6, January 13, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0019)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Adrienne Harris; Air dates: February 6-7, 1981
  - Episode #7, January 15, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0014)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Joseph H. Plock [label somewhat illegible]
  - Episode #7, January 15, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0022)
  - Episode #8, undated (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0292)
  - Episode #9, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0009)
  - Episode #10, January 19, 1981 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0291)
    Air dates: February 16-17, 1981
  - Episode #10, February 5, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0026)
    Air dates: March 9-10, 1981
  - Episode #11, January 19, 1981
    - Audio recording, January 19, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0020)
      Guest lecturer: Linda Nochler [label somewhat illegible]; Air dates: February 18-19, 1981
    - Video recording, January 19, 1981; cuid18722 (Box 262, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0446)
  - Episode #13, January 22, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0023)
    Guest lecturer: Molly Huskell [label somewhat illegible]; Air dates: February 23-24, 1981
  - Episode #14, January 22, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0005)
  - Episode #15, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0010)
    Air date: February 28, 1981
  - Episode #17, January 29, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0017)
    Guest lecturer: William Ruddish; Air dates: March 3-4, 1981
  - Episode #19, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0025)
    Guest lecturer: Susan Schechler [label somewhat illegible]
  - Episode #21, February 12, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0013)
    Air dates: March 13-14, 1981
  - Episode #22, February 25, 1981 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0293)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Naomi Bluestone; Air dates: March 16-17, 1981
  - Episode #23, February 12, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0018)
    Air dates: March 18-19, 1981
  - Episode #24, February 5, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0029)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Wendy Chankin [label somewhat illegible]; Air dates: March 20-21, 1981
  - Episode #25, March 5, 1981; cuid18723 (Box 301, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0506)
  - Episode #26, February 19, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0001)
    Guest lecturer: Barbara Lehman; Air dates: March 25-26, 1981
  - Episode #28, February 12, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0028)
    Air dates: March 30-31, 1981
  - Episode #29, February 19, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0003)
    Guest lecturers: Roslyn L. Feldberg, Dr. Evelyn Glenn [label somewhat illegible]; Air dates: April 1-2, 1981
  - Episode #30, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0015)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Madeline E. Heilman; Air dates: April 3-4, 1981
  - Episode #33, March 5, 1981 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0294)
    Guest lecturer: Meredith Tape; Air date: April 10, 1981
  - Episode #36, February 25, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0006)
    Guest lecturer: Adrienne Leaf; Air dates: April 17-18, 1981
  - Episode #37, March 19, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0021)
    Guest lecturer: Ellen Carol DuBois; April 20-21, 1981
  - Tape with illegible label, January 15, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0024)
    Air date: February 13, 1981
  - Tape with illegible label, January 19, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0002)
  - Tape with illegible label, February 2, 1981 (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0016)
    Air dates: April 6-7, 1981
  - Tape with illegible label, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0007)
  - Tape with illegible label, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0008)
  - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 5, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0027)
- "Radio, Television, and the New Technology" with Professor Dr. L. Theresa Silverman, February - March, 1981
  - Episode #10, January 12, 1981 (Box 263, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0159)
  - Episode #13, February 4, 1981 (Box 19, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0550)
  - Episode #39, March 23, 1981 (Box 57, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0415)
- "Computers: Concepts and Cultural Consequences" with Professor Nathan Hull, November, 1981
  - Episode #33, November 12, 1981 (Box 337, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0164)
  - Episode #46, November 24, 1981; cuid18724 (Box 305, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0407)
- "Experiencing Sports: A Philosophical and Cultural Analysis" with Professor Dr. Robert Gurland, November - December, 1981
  - Episode #29, November 18, 1981 (Box 298, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0167)
  - Episode #46, December 9, 1981 (Box 340, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0512)
- "Issues in European Politics" with Professor Martin Schain, January - March, 1982
  - Episode #6, January 19, 1982 (Box 339, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0523)
  - Episode #9, January 27, 1982 (Box 300, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0489)
  - Episode #33, March 24, 1982 (Box 338, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0166)
- "Developmental Psychology" with Professor Cynthia Deutsch, January - March, 1982
  - Episode #6, January 18, 1982 (Box 268, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0176)
  - Episode #25, March 15, 1982 (Box 267, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0165)
- "AL Labor", February - June, 1982
  - Episode #1 -- "A" Copy, April 13, 1982 (Box 203, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0046)
  - Episode #2 -- Air Copy, March 16, 1982 (Box 188, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0060)
  - Episode #2 -- Standby Copy, February 16, 1982 (Box 189, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0051)
  - Episode #3 -- Standby Copy, March 30, 1982 (Box 247, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0441)
  - Episode #4 -- Air Copy, March 16, 1982 (Box 89, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0540)
  - Episode #5 -- Air Copy, March 23, 1982 (Box 75, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0048)
  - Episode #5 -- Standby Copy, March 27, 1982 (Box 249, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0050)
  - Episode #6 -- Air Copy, March 23, 1982 (Box 88, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0085)
  - Episode #6 -- "B" Copy, March 23, 1982 (Box 76, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0053)
  - Episode #7 -- Standby Copy, March 16, 1982 (Box 186, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0102)
  - Episode #8 -- Air Copy, May 3, 1982 (Box 102, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0111)
  - Episode #8 -- Standby Copy, May 3, 1982 (Box 95, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0105)
  - Episode #9 -- Air Copy, March 25, 1982 (Box 87, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0101)
  - Episode #9 -- "B" Copy, March 23, 1982 (Box 79, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0127)
  - Episode #10 -- "A" Copy, April 13, 1982 (Box 173, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0081)
  - Episode #10 -- Standby Copy, April 13, 1982 (Box 138, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0087)
  - Episode #11 -- Air Copy, May 3, 1982 (Box 96, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0134)
  - Episode #11 -- Standby Copy, May 3, 1982 (Box 103, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0150)
  - Episode #12 -- "A" Copy with Film Insert, April 13, 1982 (Box 172, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0100)
  - Episode #12 -- Standby Copy, April 13, 1982 (Box 110, 1 inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0120)